

Cristian Wilgenhoff

Cristian is Software Engineer who comes from a web development background in .NET; lately he has got fascinated with the newest technologies for developing web apps using bleeding edge JavaScript stacks.

Having worked in the IT industry for 5 years as contractor for companies such as Microsoft, Deloitte, US Bank, Best Buy and Bally Technologies. His exquisite experience adds great value to your next software endeavor.

He prefers to work in real and tangible products with active clients who like to give constant feedback so their products can grow and be used by real people.

Information

- Name: Cristian Pedro Wilgenhoff
- Age: 27 years old
- Place of Residency: Argentina
- Nationality: Argentinian and Italian Dual-Citizenship
- USA VISA: B1/B2
- E-mail: <u>cpwilgenhoff@gmail.com</u>
- Phone: +54 9-2983-642518
- US-Phone: +1747-322-3040

Employment

2014 - PRESENT

Making Sense LLC, Full-Stack Engineer

- Project: Budget Maestro Contractor for Centage Full-Stack Engineer
 - Part of the development team in charge of building Budget Maestro, an application for the Business industry with the main purpose of providing budgeting solutions for companies.
 - Tasks include re-structuration of frontend architecture, integration with Bower package manager, rapid development of new features for the business logic, and creation of unit testing and E2E tests, and standardizations of the code style.
 - o The application connects to a backend designed and developed in Spring/Java.
 - o Discussions with stakeholders for feedback and feature enhancement.
 - o Technologies: AngularJS, MongoDB.
- Project: Velocity Contractor for Mobiquity, Inc Software Engineer
 - o Part of the analytics team to improve and enhance Velocity portal analytics.
 - This phase of development was aimed to fix existent reports and to add new ones into the portal.
 - o Technologies: Logi Analytics
- Project: BCP Contractor for Mobiquity, Inc Full-Stack Engineer
 - o Responsible and part of the development team of a product for the Healthcare industry named BCP (Behavior Change Platform).
 - o This product was aimed to help users change its behaviors according to a set of objectives through follow up.
 - o Part of an agile environment using two week sprints.
 - Developed integrations against the Twilio API, Fitbit API, AWS and proprietary third party API.
 - Developed unit tests in MochaJS.
 - o Technologies: NodeJS, Angular, MongoDB, Express.

Globant, Software Engineer

- Project: RGS Contractor for Bally Technologies Deployment Engineer
 - Part of the development team in charge of creating scripts for automatic deployments.
 - o Technologies: PowerShell
- Project: TV Chip Recognition Contractor for Bally Technologies Software Engineer
 - o Technologies: .NET, C# 4.0, WPF, WCF

2012 - 2013

Making Sense LLC, Software Engineer

- Developed applications for US Bank and Best Buy using the Windows Phone 7 Platform.
- Developed applications for Best Buy using Windows Phone 8.
- Front-end web development, using the Dojo Toolkit framework.
- Technologies: Windows Phone 7, Windows Phone 8, Windows 8, Dojo Toolkit

2011 - 2012

Globant, SharePoint Developer

- Responsible for the development of a custom solution using Microsoft SharePoint 2010, based on offered SharePoint BI & Enterprise Metadata Services.
- Our main goal for this development is to provide a collaborative environment that Deloitte can use to interact with their customers taxation (spreadsheet in companion of few document policiesworkflows).
- Technologies: SharePoint 2010

2010 - 2011

Glafon S.A. (Southworks), SharePoint Developer

- Responsible for the development of various business solutions based on SharePoint 2010.
- Team member of one of the developments for Microsoft during this lapse.
- Our main goal was to craft a CMS backend solution to handle video streams and schedules for the PDC 2010 Conference.
- I was also in charge of the continuous integration area within the company.
- Technologies: SharePoint 2010

Freelance Experience

PandemSim – Contractor for University of Ohio - Full-Stack Engineer Feb 2015 – April 2015

During the first quarter of 2015, I've worked as a contractor for the University of Ohio, our goal was to create a platform for students so they can perform controlled simulations of different diseases around the world, main consumers where college students and professors.

As a member of a two men team, my main role in this project was to rapidly develop features, test them and gather feedback from the stakeholders.

Regarding technology, the application stands over the latest web stack; NodeJS, AngularJS, Express, MongoDB and Socket.IO.

Reservalia - Freelance for ShoutAD Marketing - Full-Stack Engineer

March 2012 - August 2012

During 2012, I've worked as a freelance developer building a PHP application for a Restaurant. This app was fully integrated with Facebook. In it a user can easily book a table, see the menu, current offers, discounts and more details about the Restaurant. This application was developed from scratch following an MVC architecture, integrated with Facebook and Twitter API for User login. It also has a backend portal to customize it.

Midgard Alpha - University/College Assignment

In the year 2009, as an assignment for University, we've crafted a software capable of dealing with riverbed bathymetry data, based in real cases. This application was aimed to generate Delaunay triangulations from riverbed points in order to create a mesh. It was written in C++ using the Qt library, and OpenGL for 3D modeling.

Skills

Frameworks

NodeJS, Express, Socket.IO, AngularJS, Twitter Bootstrap, Dojo

Platforms

MS Windows, Linux, *Unix Environments

Languages

JavaScript, C#, HTML5, CSS3, PowerShell, Bash

Libraries/APIs

Async, MomentJS, Backbone, jQuery

Versioning Tools

Git, SVN, TFS

Package Managers

npm, Bower

Testing Tools

Karma, MochaJS, SinonJS, Jasmine, Protractor

JS Code Style Checkers

JSHint, JSCS

Continuous Integration and Automation Tools

Jenkins, Travis, Teamcity, Grunt, Gulp

DB/Storage

MongoDB v2.4 and v3.0, MySQL, SQL Server 2008

Education

2006 - 2014

Systems Engineering

National University of Central Buenos Aires (UNICEN) - Buenos Aires

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Spanish (Native)